Aleksandr Surkov

System Engineer / Administrator

Profile

Experienced IT system engineer with vast 10+ years IT experience. Skills include, IT security, computer networking, server maintenance, cloud solutions, automation, project management, web-page development, support, selling customer oriented-solutions, distribution, analytical thinking, attention to details and creative problem solving.

Mostly a self-taught techie, passionate about learning new applicable skills and new technological solutions for better tomorrow.

Employment History

IT Management / Coordinating Migration to Azure at UAB Kiwa Inspecta, Vilnius

May 2015 - Present

Responsibilities:

- Maintaining company infrastructure (VMware vSphere, HPE, Ubiquiti,

Mikrotik, VPN, Windows Active Directory, Data Loss prevention)

- Supporting and managing migration of Infrastructure to MS Azure Cloud (O365, D365, Sharepoint, Azure AD, MS Dynamics, Azure RMS)

Project Manager at UAB Mocron, Vilnius

July 2013 - Present

Responsibilities:

- Search for new IT products and partners
- Product delivery, distribution and sales from (Italy, Germany, UK, Budapest, Latvia, Poland),
- Selling customer oriented-solutions (IT Security, Data Leakage Prevention, Servers, Cloud solutions)
- Strategic planning

Details

+370 663 51615

aleksandr.surkov@outlook.com

Date of birth

1987-05-12

Driving license

В

Links

LinkedIn

Skills

Analytical Thinking

Time Management

IT Service Management

Able to Operate Under Pressure

B2B Sales

Logical Thinking

Computer Programming

Languages

Lithuanian

Russian

English

Hobbies

Motivational Books, Crafts, Martial-Arts, Car-Travelling

System Administrator at Vilnius County Adomas Mickevicius Public Library System Administrator, Vilnius

March 2008 - Present

Responsibilities:

- Maintaining company infrastructure (VMware vSphere, HPE, Ubiquiti,

Mikrotik, Windows Active Directory, VLAN, WAN, VPN, VOIP,)

- Public WiFi Management (Content Access and Security for kids and adults)
- Leading technical projects
- Purchasing process management, Assets management
- Websites / Intranet support and development
- End-user Education (Security, Cloud. Corporate Data etc.)

Project Coordinator at The National Library of Lithuania | Lietuvos nacionalinė Martyno Mažvydo biblioteka, Vilnius

January 2009 - January 2011

Responsibilities:

- Managing IT integration of project "Libraries for Innovation

Education

Bachelor's Degree, International School of Law and Business, Vilnius

September 2005 - August 2008

Programming and Business management · (2005 - 2008)

Certification

Sophos Certified Architect

April 2019 - April 2019

Lithuania

Sophos Lithuania

Hands on Hack IT to Defend IT (L1)

November 2018 - November 2018

Lithuania

Cyber Security Academy Lietuva

MikroTik Certified Routing Engineer (MTCRE)

January 2018 – January 2018 Latvia

MikroTik Certified Network Associate (MTCNA)

October 2017 - October 2017

Latvia

Courses

Java From Scrach, Software Development Academy

March 2019 - Present

Projects

User data parser / Converter / Specific output builder

2019 - 2019

Goal was to have a UI tool that can quickly parse a big amount of user data(~10K fields), recheck it by specific rules, perform manipulation with it (RegEx, Hex2Dec, etc.), and build output in comma - separated values for other software understandable structure.

Used: Java, JavaFX, RegEx

Results:

- Shortened data conversion to a seconds
- Accuracy gained;
- Automated data check and rule application
- No more (n++ hours) of Excel-Spreadsheet manual data re-building, checking and human errors:)

Intranet for private communication within organization V.2

2017 - 2017

Main goal of this project was to rebuild from scratch previous version V.1 and implement new features for intranet collaboration system (~80 employees)

In this version wanted simplify user crete/delete/manage procedure by merging users with MS Active Directory. Implement RBAC (Role Based Access Conrol) for specific sectors. Calendar and Events integration.

Used: PHP, MySQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Apache, CentOS, MS Active Directory, LDAP, Wordpress. List.js API.

Results:

- Active Directory Integration (users created in AD are fetched LDAP by Cron and appears in Intranet System)
- Calendar and Events Integration for fast Info about what is Scheduled, (all internal events, place booking)
- Role-based access control implementation for "who can do what" on Intranet System.
- Users can login to intranet system with AD accounts
- Users can managed their own profile data, (picture, phone, email, job title, about..etc.)
- On main page up to 4 upcoming employee birthdays are displayed
- Contact Search List is now fully Dynamic (by latest user profile info) and fast on search by using List.js API
- New place for storing internal documentation
- New news feed + ability to leave a comment if logged-in + press "Like/Love" news without login
- New Stuff section (to share non work info, sales etc.)
- New Responsive Design + Mobile friendly

Website: vmc.lt

2016 - 2016

Goal: create new website for company, manage each stage of this project.

Result:- New responsive website

- Email security from web crawler bots (Caesar cipher used)
- Website code and image optimization / SEO
- Google maps integration for location view

Intranet for private communication within organization V.1

2015 - 2016

The main goal of this project was to create a closed intranet collaboration, news platform for employees and achieve usage of it. (~80 employees)

Used: PHP, MySQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Apache, ClearOS, Linux.

Results:

- Usage achieved
- Faster internal info spread
- Platform stability
- Fast employee contact search by any field (List.js API Integration)

House light control over network web UI on Arduino

2014 - 2015

Project descriptionArduino project to control house light

Hardware used: Arduino Mega 2560 Rev3, Arduino ethernet shield, microSD, Relay board, Router

Skills used: C/C++, HTML, CSS, JQuery, XML, TCP/IP.

Results:

- Able to turn on/off light thru WEB UI
- Able to turn on/off light thru physical wall switch
- Instant WEB UI light status change without page Refresh
- Fast System Recovery after Electricity Loss/Reboot
- No Switch Contact Debouncing